<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backbone Tours</title>
    <description>Tours and activities around the famous backbone trail in Malibu, CA</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 12:15:19 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 12:15:19 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Calabasas Peak</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/calabasas_peak/calabasas_peak_map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calabasas peak stands alone at 2,163 ft offering 360 degree panoramic views of the santa monica mountains, calabasas, the coastline and greater los angeles basin. The hike starts at a parking lot off stunt road just about a mile or two passed mullholland hwy. The trail begins on the other side of stunt road from the parking lot and goes up.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/calabasas_peak/start.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Start&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is about 1,000 feet of elevation gain to the top so bring plenty of water and don’t go on a day where it is hotter than 75 degrees, there is no shade. Looking ahead you will see the top of the peak the whole time.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/calabasas_peak/half_way.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Almost there&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go during spring you can see lots of wild flowers such as the common goldfields pictured below.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/calabasas_peak/common_goldfields.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get close to top look to your right and you will see the pyramid of caves. At the top of ridge take a small trail that goes off to the left. This will take you to top of calabasas peak which is only another 10 minutes. Once at the top enjoy the view. There is also a lockbox which has poems and a journal with messages left by others. Feel free to add your adventure and read about that of others.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/calabasas_peak/at_peak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are ready take the same route back to the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 2 hours
Difficulty: Moderate
Bring: Hiking shoes, hat, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/calabassas_peak/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/calabassas_peak/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wild Flowers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Of course the iconic California Poppy pictured above is known all over the world but what isn’t so well know is the tremendous wild flower diversity, especially in the santa monica mountains. The best time for seeing wildflowers is spring, specifically mid February through April with March being the best month. Many people don’t realize the vast amount of wild flowers that bloom and transformation that occurs every spring, turning golden hills, green with flowers everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I have photographed the wild flowers that are common in this area and found on backbone trails hikes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;California Fucshia&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/california_fucshia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;California Fucshia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bull Thistle&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/bull_thistle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bull Thistle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bush Poppy&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/bush_poppy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bush Poppy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canyon Sunflower&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/canyon_sunflower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canyon Sunflower&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaparrel Nightdhade&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/chaparrel_nightshade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chaparrel Nightshade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;California Prickly Phlox&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/california_prickly_phlox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;California Prickly Phlox&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost Indian Paintbrush&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/coast_indian_paintbrush.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coast Indian Paintbrush&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giant Coreopis&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/giant_coreopis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Giant Coreopis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grape Soda Lupine&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/grape_soda_lupine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grape Soda Lupine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heartleaf Keckiella&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/heartleaf_keckiella.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heartleaf Keckiella&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hummingbird Sage&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/hummingbird_sage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hummingbird Sage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission Prickly Pear&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/mission_prickly_pear.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIssion Prickly Pear&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monkey Flower&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/monkey_flower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Monkey Flower&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning Glory&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/morning_glory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Morning Glory&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purple Sage&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/purple_sage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Purple Sage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spanish Broom&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/spanish_broom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spanish Broom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunflower&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/sunflower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunflower&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two Tone Everlasting&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wild_flowers/two_tone_everlasting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tow Tone Everlasting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wild_flowers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/wild_flowers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Saddle Peak</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/saddle_peak/saddle_peak_map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saddle peak stands at 2,805 ft and is one of the highest peaks in the santa monica mountains. The hike starts off stunt road about 3 or 4 miles passed the mullholland hwy intersection. The trail starts at the piuma road sign. You can park on either side of stunt road.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/saddle_peak/piuma_rd_sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Start&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 10 minutes you will reach a fork, take the trail left to saddle peak.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/saddle_peak/saddle_peak_sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Saddle Peak Fork&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to your left you can see calabasas peak across the way.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/saddle_peak/calabasas_peak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are getting close you will see saddle rock. This is also a popular rock climb as it offers several hundred foot faces.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/saddle_peak/saddle_rock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Saddle Rock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you get to saddle rock area you will see lots of small caves as you make your way toward the summit. If you got kids with you they will love this part.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/saddle_peak/caves.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Caves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you reach the ridge line continue to your right toward the ocean and the weather station. Take a left at the fork to the weather station and this will take you up to saddle peak.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/saddle_peak/saddle_peak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Saddle Peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spring there are beautiful wildflowers such as purple mat, pictured below.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/saddle_peak/purple_mat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Saddle Rock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the amazing views, hopefully you brought a snack and something to enjoy. When you are ready follow the same path back to your car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 2 hours
Difficulty: Moderate
Bring: Hiking shoes, hat, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/saddle_peak/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/saddle_peak/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Point Dume Reserve</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_dume_reserve/pt_dume_preserve_map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located at the tip of point dume, separating westward beach and big / little dume the point dume reserve offers breath taking ocean and mountain views from bluffs above some of souther california’s more remote beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hike starts at a small parking lot off cliffside drive. I recommend parking further away off dume drive since there are only limited spots. Also they enforce parking tickets and after sunset you will get a ticket which is no bueno. You do want to see the sunset right?
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_dume_reserve/pt_dume_reserve_sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Parking Lot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the path heading to your left and stay to your left. You will see a view of little dume beach and follow a narrow trail to your left that goes along the cliffs.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_dume_reserve/little_dume_beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Little Dume&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get to the cliffs take new stair case if it open otherwise follow trail to right. This will take you down a path where you will find ropes to help you get down to little dume via the “death stairs”. Once at the beach you can explore some tide pools and walk along the beach. Little dume was for a long time more inaccessible to public and considered a private beach. Above the high tide line is still private but below high tide line is considered public so please respect the local residents.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_dume_reserve/little_dume.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Little dume beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here go back the way you came and when you are back on the cliffs continue to your left.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_dume_reserve/path_to_top_big_dume.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Path to Big Dume&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are at the top you will see views of catalina island, big dume and zuma beach. On a really clear day you can also see anacapa and sanat Cruz islands which are part of the channel islands.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_dume_reserve/top_of_point_dume.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Point Dume&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In front of the point dume state park monument is a narrow path that leads down to trail which wraps around the point. If you look to you left and below you can see a beach cove which is called secret beach or pirates cove (it is accessible via westward beach). The trail will split go to your left. This will take you down to westward beach.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_dume_reserve/westward_beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Westward beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you timed it right it should be close to sunset. There is a restaurant called the sunset which is a local spot, the food isn’t great but they make great drinks. When you are done head back up the way you came and once you reach a fork go left. This will take you back to cliffside drive where you started from.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_dume_reserve/path_from_westward_beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spring bloom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head to your left on bird view drive and make a right on sea lion place. Finally a left on dume drive and you are back at your car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 2 hours
Difficulty: Easy
Bring: Good shoes, beach clothing, hat, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pt_dume_reserve_hike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pt_dume_reserve_hike/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tuna Canyon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tuna_canyon_hike/tuna_canyon_map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hike starts close to 3233 Tuna Canyon Rd. You will see cars parked on the right which is where the big rock trail begins. You will first go through some oak tree meadows.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tuna_canyon_hike/start.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oak Trees&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes the trail opens up and you are greeted by stunning ocean and mountain panorama. The budwood trail will split from big rock trail, follow it to your left. This is the nicer and more scenic of the two paths.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tuna_canyon_hike/trail_path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trail path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several smaller paths that go left you can take those or decide to stay on the main trail, it all goes to same place. Looking to your right you can see the malibu pier and point dume in the distance. To your left will be the los angeles bay and santa monica.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tuna_canyon_hike/los_angeles_bay.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Los Angeles Bay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 45 minutes you reach the end of the trail. You will see a heart, made of rocks with a breathtaking view of catalina island. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tuna_canyon_hike/heart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Point dume&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To your left you can see culver city and beyond it, downtown LA. On a really clear winter day you can see a snow capped mount baldly in the far distance.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tuna_canyon_hike/downtown_la.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oak Trees&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are ready to go back take the same trail but stay on main trail this time to your left. If you took the side trails on way down then most of way back will be different which makes the hike even more enjoyable. Once you get back to big rock trail go right. After you are back in the car continue on tuna canyon road, stay to your right and take the one way road down tuna canyon to PCH. It is an amazing drive and one few people get to experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 1.5 hours
Difficulty: Easy
Bring: Good shoes, hat, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tuna_canyon_hike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tuna_canyon_hike/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Point Mugu Peak</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/pt_mugu_peak_map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located in the point mugu state park, this is an out and back with a loop around the majestic point mugu peak. Towering 1,266 ft above the pacific point mugu peak offers panoramic views of the coastline and channel islands. On a clear day you can see Catalina, San Nicholas, Anacapa and Santa Cruz islands. Point mugu peak is so close to the coastline you feel like you are flying above the ocean, it is truly an amazing out of body experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hike starts at a dirt parking lot and the trail is called the chumash trail.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/start.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Parking Lot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trail has a very steep ascend, if you aren’t used to hiking you will want to go slow and take a lot of breaks. I would also avoid this hike on a hot day, there is no shade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you ascend don’t forget to turn around you will be treated with a great view ocean view, the mugu wetlands and in the distance channel islands (on a clear day).
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_ascend_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mugu Wetlands&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 45 minutes you will reach the base of point mugu peak and a fork in the road. Go to your left and a few hundred feet down road go right and take the single track switch back up point mugu peak.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_ascend_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;North Side of Point Mugu Peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you make it up the first part your are almost there and in the home stretch. From here you have an amazing view of point mugu in the distance. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_ascend_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Point Mugu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you come during spring you can see the cactus flowers bluming.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/cactus_flower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus Blume&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally it is time to celebrate and enjoy a snack with quite a spectacular view. The peak is very flat and to the right is a nice little bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North view on to anacapa, santa cruz islands and point mugu.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_north_view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Point Mugu Peak North View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South view of sandy dunes in the distance.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_south_view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;South Side of Point Mugu Peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;East view of sandstone peak
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/sandstone_peak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sandstone Peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are ready to head back continue on the trail south. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_descend_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;South View 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_descend_view_south.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;South View 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 5-10 minutes you get to another fork, go to your right. You will soon pass by what I think is the best view. A smal trail to the left goes to an amazing lookout by some rocks.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_descend_view_down.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking Down&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After joining back with main trail you will continue to traverse, I find this part the most amazing as you are looking out over the ocean the entire time.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_descend_trail_traverse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Descending trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another 15-20 minutes on the trail you will make it back to the first fork, continue left down to the parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 3 hours
Difficulty: Hard
Bring: Hiking boots, hat, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pt_magu_peak_hike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pt_magu_peak_hike/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Point Mugu Ocean Vista</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located in the point mugu state park, this magnificent hike offers breathtaking ocean vista views in one of the most scenic areas and less frequented areas in all of southern california. Traversing the backbone trail you will assend with terrif views of Pt. mugu peak and the coastline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Park in La Jolla Canyon, day parking area. Follow the road into the canyon and look for the sign to ray miller trailhead. Take the ray miller trail heading south (to the right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trail will ascend to the ridgeline. Behind you is point mugu peak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pt. mugu peak
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/pt_mugu_peak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pt. mugu peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 45 minutes you should reach a fork go right at the overlook trail. 15 minutes later you will reach another fork this will be our loop. Take fireline trail. This will descend into the canyon and eventually reach sycamore canyon, go right all the way to the sycamore canyon beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sycamore Cove Beach
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/sycamore_cove_beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sycamore Cove beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you brought some beach wear to enjoy the refreshing pacific and a nice lunch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head back up sycamore canyon but this time hang left on the scenic trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vista overlooking the Backbone trail
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/backbone_trail_pt_mugu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vista&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will see magnificient costal views, pt. mugu rock, the sandy dunes and a glimpse of sandstone peak. At 3,111 ft this is the highest peak in the Santa Monica mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pt. mugu Rock
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/pt_mugu_rock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pt. mugu rock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandy Dunes
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/sandy_dune.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sandy Dunes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandstone Peak
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/sandstone_peak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sandstone peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scenic trail will work stay to your left on the overlook trail. This will take you back to the end of the loop at the fireline trail. This time go left staying on the overlook trail. Again you will reach a fork, take a left on to the backbone trail which takes you back top the ray miller trailhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 6 hours
Difficulty: Moderate
Bring: Hiking boots, beach wear, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pt_magu_ocean_vista_hike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pt_magu_ocean_vista_hike/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mash Movie</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/mash_movie_map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located in malibu creek state park this hike takes you back to the glory days of hollywood. Countless movies and TV series were filmed in the park such as planet of the apes, the original tarzan and of course mash. This hike starts at grasslands trailhead on mullholland hwy where it meets malibu canyon. You can park on the side of the road on mullholland hwy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very easy hike which is mostly flat. It is an out and back. Once on the trail you will get to a small hill that heads to the right. At the top of the hill 10 minutes from trailhead the trail will fork, take the middle trail which goes down into the main park area. You should see the beuatiful malibu creek in front of you. As you go down look to your right at a truly awe inspiring california oak. The hillside to the left on the other side of the creek is where planet of the apes was filmed by the rocky areas.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/oak_fall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;California Oak in Fall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/oak_spring.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Califnornia Oak in Spring&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you reach the bottom you will join Crags road, go to your right. After another 10-15 minutes you will reach the main area and another fork, continue on Crags rd to your right which will go up a small incline. After another 10-15 minutes you will reach century dam.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/century_dam_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Century Dam from above&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top of the incline you will see a small path going to your left which goes down to century dam. This is a great spot for a quick snack and to admire the tranqulity.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/century_dam_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Century Dam from below&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue down the path which after 5 minutes will meet up with crags road. Conitnue down crags road and in about 20 minutes you will need to cross the malibu creek. There is a large log that you need to balance across. It is possible to fall into the creek (don’t worry it is shallow) but bring a towel and some extra socks. After crossing the creek you are almost there, it should be another 20 minutes to the mash site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first vehicle is a replica which was recently added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little further is the main area. There are picnic benches and of course an original mash jeep as well as a medic.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/mash_original_medic_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mash Original Medic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/mash_original_medic_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mash Original Medic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go during spring you will see lots of California poppy’s and other wild flowers blooming everywhere.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/poppy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Califnornia Poppy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On your way back once passed century dam and down the incline go straight. This will take you to the park visitor center. This property used to be owned by paramont studios and was used for lodging as well as entertaining. Even Mariyln Monroe stayed there so it is definitely worth checking out!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/malibu_creek.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Malibu Creek&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 3 hours
Difficulty: Easy
Bring: Hiking boots, towel, extra socks, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/mash-movie-hike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/mash-movie-hike/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sandstone Peak</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sandstone_peak_hike/sandstone_peak_map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trail Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandstone peak is the highest mountain in the santa monica mountains at 3,111 ft. The trailhead starts around 2,000 ft. It is about a 1,111 ft up elevation gain. The trail is an out and back but you can make a longer loop to extend your tour. The hike has very limited shade so it isn’t recommended when it is too hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trail will ascend very quickly. The first part is the most challenging but then it gets more gradual. Enjoy some breathtaking views of the santa monica mountains and rugged costaline.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sandstone_peak_hike/sun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Valley View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 30 minutes into the trail to your right is Malibu lake which is a very secluded area off mullholand hwy and home to many famous people that are low key.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sandstone_peak_hike/malibu_lake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Malibu Lake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a clear day you will get a great view of catalina island jolting out of the pacific.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sandstone_peak_hike/catalina.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Catalina Island&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last part of the hike is a single track scamper up to the peak. If you want to go to highest point some bouldering is required, nothing crazy but be careful. The views at the highest perch in the santa monica mountains are breathtaking. You feel like an eagle on top of the world, soaring.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sandstone_peak_hike/yerba_buena.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yerba Buena Canyone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 3 hours
Difficulty: Moderate
Bring: Hiking boots, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/sandstone-peak/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/sandstone-peak/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
