<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backbone Tours</title>
    <description>Tours and activities around the famous backbone trail in Malibu, CA</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:02:36 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:02:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Point mugu Peak Hike</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Located in the point mugu state park, this is an out and back with a loop around the majestic point mugu peak. Towering 1,266 ft above the pacific point mugu peak offers panoramic views of the coastline and channel islands. On a clear day you can see Catalina, San Nicholas, Anacapa and Santa Cruz islands. Point mugu peak is so close to the coastline you feel like you are flying above the ocean, it is truly an amazing out of body experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hike starts at a dirt parking lot and the trail is called the chumash trail.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/start.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Parking Lot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trail has a very steep ascend, if you aren’t used to hiking you will want to go slow and take a lot of breaks. I would also avoid this hike on a hot day, there is no shade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you ascend don’t forget to turn around you will be treated with a great view ocean view, the mugu wetlands and in the distance channel islands (on a clear day).
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_ascend_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mugu Wetlands&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 45 minutes you will reach the base of point mugu peak and a fork in the road. Go to your left and a few hundred feet down road go right and take the single track switch back up point mugu peak.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_ascend_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;North Side of Point Mugu Peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you make it up the first part your are almost there and in the home stretch. From here you have an amazing view of point mugu in the distance. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_ascend_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Point Mugu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you come during spring you can see the cactus flowers bluming.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/cactus_flower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cactus Blume&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally it is time to celebrate and enjoy a snack with quite a spectacular view. The peak is very flat and to the right is a nice little bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North view on to anacapa, santa cruz islands and point mugu.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_north_view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Point Mugu Peak North View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South view of sandy dunes in the distance.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_south_view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;South Side of Point Mugu Peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;East view of sandstone peak
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/sandstone_peak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sandstone Peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are ready to head back continue on the trail south. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_descend_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;South View 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_descend_view_south.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;South View 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 5-10 minutes you get to another fork, go to your right. You will soon pass by what I think is the best view. A smal trail to the left goes to an amazing lookout by some rocks.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_descend_view_down.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking Down&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After joining back with main trail you will continue to traverse, I find this part the most amazing as you are looking out over the ocean the entire time.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_peak_hike/peak_descend_trail_traverse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Descending trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another 15-20 minutes on the trail you will make it back to the first fork, continue left down to the parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 3 hours
Difficulty: difficult
Bring: Hiking boots, hat, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pt_magu_peak_hike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pt_magu_peak_hike/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Point mugu Ocean Vista Hike</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Located in the point mugu state park, this magnificent hike offers breathtaking ocean vista views in one of the most scenic areas and less frequented areas in all of southern california. Traversing the backbone trail you will assend with terrif views of Pt. mugu peak and the coastline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pt. mugu peak
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/pt_mugu_peak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pt. mugu peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vista overlooking the Backbone trail
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/backbone_trail_pt_mugu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vista&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One the ridgeline is reached we will slowly decend making our way to the beach. You will see magnificient costal views, pt. mugu rock, the sandy dunes and a glimpse of sandstone peak. At 3,111 ft this is the highest peak in the Santa Monica mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pt. mugu Rock
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/pt_mugu_rock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pt. mugu rock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandy Dunes
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/sandy_dune.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sandy Dunes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandstone Peak
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/sandstone_peak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sandstone peak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally after an awesome hike what better way to relax the taking off those boots, dipping those toes in the refreshing pacific and lounging on the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sycamore Cove Beach
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pt_mugu_ocean_vista_hike/sycamore_cove_beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sycamore Cove beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 6 hours
Difficulty: moderate
Bring: Hiking boots, beach wear, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pt_magu_ocean_vista_hike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pt_magu_ocean_vista_hike/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mash Movie Hike</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Located in malibu creek state park this hike takes you back to the glory days of hollywood. Countless movies and TV series were filmed in the park such as planet of the apes, the original tarzan and of course mash. This hike starts at grasslands trailhead on mullholland hwy where it meets malibu canyon. You can park on the side of the road on mullholland hwy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very easy hike which is mostly flat. It is an out and back. Once on the trail you will get to a small hill that heads to the right. At the top of the hill 10 minutes from trailhead the trail will fork, take the middle trail which goes down into the main park area. You should see the beuatiful malibu creek in front of you. As you go down look to your right at a truly awe inspiring california oak. The hillside to the left on the other side of the creek is where planet of the apes was filmed by the rocky areas.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/oak_fall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;California Oak in Fall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/oak_spring.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Califnornia Oak in Spring&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you reach the bottom you will join Crags road, go to your right. After another 10-15 minutes you will reach the main area and another fork, continue on Crags rd to your right which will go up a small incline. After another 10-15 minutes you will reach century dam.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/century_dam_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Century Dam from above&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top of the incline you will see a small path going to your left which goes down to century dam. This is a great spot for a quick snack and to admire the tranqulity.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/century_dam_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Century Dam from below&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue down the path which after 5 minutes will meet up with crags road. Conitnue down crags road and in about 20 minutes you will need to cross the malibu creek. There is a large log that you need to balance across. It is possible to fall into the creek (don’t worry it is shallow) but bring a towel and some extra socks. After crossing the creek you are almost there, it should be another 20 minutes to the mash site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first vehicle is a replica which was recently added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little further is the main area. There are picnic benches and of course an original mash jeep as well as a medic.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/mash_original_medic_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mash Original Medic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/mash_original_medic_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mash Original Medic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go during spring you will see lots of California poppy’s and other wild flowers blooming everywhere.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/poppy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Califnornia Poppy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On your way back once passed century dam and down the incline go straight. This will take you to the park visitor center. This property used to be owned by paramont studios and was used for lodging as well as entertaining. Even Mariyln Monroe stayed there so it is definitely worth checking out!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mash_movie_hike/malibu_creek.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Malibu Creek&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Activity: Hiking
Duration: 3 hours
Difficulty: Easy
Bring: Hiking boots, towel, extra socks, water and snacks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/mash-movie-hike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/mash-movie-hike/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
